Parijat Prashun Purohit

LinkedIn | GitHub | UVA Online Judge

Location: Calgary, AB, Canada Email: parijat2009@gmail.com | Cell: 403-332-3588

Highly skilled Python backend developer with over 5 years of experience in contributing to projects using Django and Flask Frameworks. Seeking opportunities to continue developing expertise in backend development and open to Frontend or Full Stack positions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

: C, Python Languages **Frameworks** : Django, Flask **Database** : PostgreSQL

Version Control: Github, Gitlab, Azure Repos (Azure Devops)

Dev Tools : Docker, Celery, Redis, Casbin, WebSocket, RabbitMQ

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intermediate Technical Developer

Jonah Group Ltd.

May 2022 - Feb 2023 Remote - Toronto, ON, Canada

- Designed and implemented a scalable backend architecture using Docker and Django multitenancy. The architecture utilized a single database with multiple schemas to enable efficient data isolation and management across different tenants. Authorization was implemented using JWT tokens, and the multitenant architecture utilized class-based permission controls.
- · Developed the backend APIs for messaging and video appointment applications. The messaging application was implemented using Websocket protocol for real-time communication and Redis for in-memory caching. The online video appointment application utilized **Twilio**'s RESTful APIs, contributing to the implementation of key features such as real-time video communication and scheduling management.
- Contributed to the **Equifax** identity verification microservice to analyze potential investor financial status using Flask framework. A similar microservice was developed that integrated with Plaid to enable linking of investor bank accounts and generation of summarized activity reports.
- · Implemented permission policies using Casbin with the Pony adapter to ensure secure access control for a web application.

Software Developer

Farmers Edge Inc.

Jan 2018 – May 2022 Lethbridge, AB, Canada

- Developed and implemented **RESTful API**s for digital farming solutions using the **Django** framework. Collaborated with the team throughout the software development lifecycle, from planning and code review to QA testing, deployment, and bug fixing.
- Developed a microservice in **Flask** to retrieve hail and rain data from **IBM Weather APIs**, determined the location using geo data, and stored the information for insurance claim decision based on client's geometric data.
- Designed and implemented a notification system using Celery and asynchronous programming techniques that sends daily or event-based notifications to users based on their preferences.
- Worked on integrating JohnDeere APIs to fetch and store data from agricultural machines, and developed analytical tools to gain insights into machine performance and optimize farm operations using **OAuth** flow

EDUCATION

University of Lethbridge

M.Sc in Computer Science

CGPA: 4.00/4.00

Lethbridge, AB, Canada 2015 - 2017

Chittagong University of Engineering & Technology

B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering

CGPA: 3.90/4.00

Chittagong, Bangladesh 2010 - 2014